David Gordon

Las Vegas, NV - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/David-Gordon/924ad180bd6846f7

I have over twenty years of experience in all phases of the implementation and management of HCM, workforce management, benefits administration, time tracking, and payroll applications. I have served in the roles of Portfolio Manager, Program Manager, Engagement Manager, Project Manager, Team Lead, and Principal Consultant. My primary focus has been on project management, analysis, fit/gap, design and implementation for large Workday, PeopleSoft, ADP Enterprise, and other HCM, time tracking, applicant tracking, and payroll solution implementations. I am available for projects in the Pacific and Mountain time zones, only.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Workday HCM Project Management Consultant

The Practicing IT Project Manager LLC - 2013 to Present

Workday HCM project management consultant. Guided stabilization and optimization for a pharmaceutical company with operations in eight countries during their first year on Workday. Provided recommendations on a three year HR technology road map for a global company expanding through mergers and acquisitions. Managed the Workday implementation through the Plan and Architect stages for an internet services company. Blogger and content curator at The Practicing IT Project Manager.

Workday Engagement Manager

Collaborative Solutions - 2011 to 2013

Workday engagement manager, leading HCM implementation and optimization projects involving HCM, benefits administration, payroll, time tracking, absence management, ESS / MSS / mobile, and a variety of integration types, such as third party administrators and providers, applicant tracking (Kenexa, Taleo, Brassring) and learning management systems (Cornerstone), time tracking (Kronos), and SSO/SAML services. Customers include a technology manufacturer with operations in over sixty countries, an auto parts manufacturer with operations in twenty countries, a technology company with operations in ten countries, a logistics property management firm with operations in twenty countries, two financial services firms with international operations, and two insurance carriers with domestic U.S. operations.

Director of HR / Payroll Solutions

MGM Resorts International - 2006 to 2011

The interface between IT and the business leaders, and HCM and Payroll project portfolio manager. Hired and led a team of project managers responsible for ideation, prioritization, funding, and executing a portfolio of HRIS projects totaling over \$18M over four years. Projects included a program to standardize configuration of Infinium HR/PY and Documentum, used at 17 different resorts and migrate them to a single server; replacement of three unsupported timekeeping systems with Kronos iSeries Gaming Suite; replacing obsolete and unsupported time clocks with Kronos terminals; implementing the HRLogix applicant tracking solution and related business process re-engineering; outsourcing of benefits administration to Aon; and various upgrade and maintenance projects.

Senior Project Manager

Exult / Hewitt Associates - 2004 to 2006

Responsible for managing transformation projects, in support of HR BPO contracts. Negotiated SOW's and managed efforts of multiple vendors providing software and product experts, and the efforts of internal hosting data center teams, client SME's, testers, and account team IT and functional staff spread across five time

zones. Managed implementation of Workbrain time tracking for an energy utility. Managed conversion of a PeopleSoft implementation for a retail chain, in support of an HR BPO contract.

Principal Consultant

ADP - 2001 to 2004

Project manager or team lead on six ADP Enterprise implementation projects for clients in a variety of industries, including commercial property management, retail, manufacturing, heavy construction, technology, and utilities. Managed a PeopleSoft Pension Administration project for a tire manufacturer.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Technology

Capella University 2010

Bachelor of Science in Business Management

University of Maryland 1984

SKILLS

Workday deployment methodology Agile Development Project Management Business Process Improvement Integration Requirements Management Financial Analysis Risk Management

LINKS

http://www.practicingitpm.com

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

PMP

SPHR

GPHR

CEBS

PUBLICATIONS

The Data Conversion Cycle: A guide to migrating transactions and other records, for system implementation teams

December 2014

MS Project Hacks

November 2014

52 Tips to Break Into Project Management (co-author)

June 2014

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Extensive experience managing virtual and co-located blended teams from multiple vendors and business units across multiple time zones. Negotiate and manage the execution of contracts and SOW's, from both vendor and customer roles. Extensive domain knowledge in global human resources management, employee benefits administration, and payroll for multi-national employers.